Ronaldo.
ロナルド
Bring my brother back to the family.
兄さんをファミリーに戻してあげて
ネロがガラッシアに忠誠を誓えば
If Nero swears loyalty to the Galassias, I'll let him live.
命だけは助けてやる
However Frate's the next don and down the line...
が 次のドンはフラテだ そしてゆくゆくは...
I just don't want to see our family fighting anymore.
家族で争うのだけはもう見たくないの
Please...
お願い
It's all up to Nero.
すべてはネロ次第だ
If he submits...
奴は跪くなら
kanjou ni tsukeru
I can assign whatever name I wish
namae wa jiyuu dane
To these emotions.
hora kawarihateta
See, they've already ceased to change.
kesenai boku no
The trigger of
tsumi no hikigane ga
My unrepentable sins
toketeshimaisou de
Seems ready to melt away,
nikushimi ga kieteshimattara
But if this hatefulness fades,
kimi o korosenai kara
I'll lose my chance to kill you.
kako o tannou shiteiru
I'm experiencing every moment of my past,
tsumi ga tsukutta boku ni kawaru tame ni
Trying to become the person who created these sins
ASL no naifu de
With an ASL knife.
kioku no signal kizamareteru noni
Despite the signal carved into my memories,
itami sae keshisatteshimau kizuna no spiral
Even the pain is erased away by this spiral of causality.
Having wandered in, I begin to fade... ceasing to be myself.
mayoikonda boku wa boku de kietekureteiku
A Poor Player
悲哀的演員
The trick to squeezing a lemon is to roll it in your hands for thirty seconds,
しぼる骨はレモンを30秒を転がしてやるんだ
exerting just a little pressure.
少し力を入れてな
That'll make it less bitter.
そうすると 苦味が減る
Now it's perfect!
これで完璧
Go on, eat up!
さ 食ってくれ
I want to thank you guys.
今日はお前たちを労いたい
We gladly accept.
遠慮なくいただくぜ
I really am grateful
本当に感謝してるんだぜ
you took care of Orco.
オルコを片付けられたんだからな
Thanks to you, right now...
お陰で 俺は今や
I'm the king!
キングだ
The flavor's about the same.
味は落ちてねぇな
Yeah.
Hey, did you know?
ねね そう言えば知ってる
This cheese was imported from Puglia in southern Italy.
このチーズ 南イタリアのプーリアから取り寄せたのよ
You know Puglia? It's in the heel of the boot,
知ってるかしら イタリアの踵のところ
and it was a relative of Rudolph Valentino's.
でね ルドルフ バレンティノと親戚だったのよ
You can see the resemblance in the eyes, right?
目元とか似てない
この人のママも澄み切ったアドリア海みたいに
His mama had that color, too.
Like the Adriatic Sea, so pure—
とっても純粋な
Now we take out the Vanetti family.
後はバネッチィ ファミリーだ
We're a team now.
俺達は仲間だ 生きてる限りの
As long as we live...
More like roommates, right?
それを言うなら ルームメイトだろう
As long as I'm renting a room from you.
部屋を借りてる限り
Right?
Either way, I want you to—
どっちにしろ 存分...
I want you to go out and make trouble.
存分に暴れて頂戴
I'm counting on you.
期待してるは
Well, wouldn't want to let you down.
じゃ 期待に応えなきゃな
Don't you want your drink?
もう酒はいいのか?
Nah, I've had enough.
あ 十分だ
That's right! You've got some
pretty great booze, don't you?
そうだよな お前ら 随分に酒持ってんだもんな
Hey, let me have some next time!
ね 今度 飲ませて頂戴
That damn Fango.
ファンゴの野郎
He's gonna run us ragged,
俺達を俺達を徹底的に使い倒す気でいやがる
and he'll try to steal Lawless Heaven from us.
このままじゃ ローレス ヘブンもとられる
Then, once we're no longer useful...
そして 用が済んだら...
What do you advise?
お前なら どうする
In the end, the Vanetti family is the only place we can rest easy.
結局 安息の地はバネッチィ ファミリーにしかない
The problem is Frate and Ronaldo.
問題はフラテとロナルドだ
What an awful state...
酷いな
Hey, what's wrong, Caesar?
おいおい どうしたシーザー
You looked so bold when you were casting the die.
賽を投げた時は勇ましかったのにな
Seems a little late for regrets.
今更後悔か?
Frate, you have some good points that Nero lacks.
フラテ お前にはネロにない いいところがある
Like what?
どんな
You're sincere.
素直なとことだ
That's what I first liked about you.
俺が気に入ったのはそこだ
You're the only one who really
worries about the family, right?
本当にファミリーを心配してるのはお前だろう
So you need to kill Nero.
なら ネロをやるんだ
You're the only one who can save the family.
ファミリーを救えるのは お前しかいない
Take this and get some rest.
これを飲んで ゆっくり休め
Lawless Heaven, please.
ローレス ヘブンをくれ
I just hit the jackpot! Gimme a whole bottle!
バカづき:打麻雀用語,意思是行大運.
今日は バカづきしたからよ ボトルでくれ
If you want to drink that, go to one of Fango's bars.
あの酒が飲みたきゃ ファンゴの店に行け
逆だろう
That's backwards, ain't it?
Vanetti bars are the only ones that deal in—
ありゃ バネッチィの店でしか扱ってないんじゃなかっ...
Hey.
暫くの間でいい
Why not buy from Fango just for a little while?
ファンゴんとこから仕入れてくれねぇか
We'll do you right.
悪いようにはしねぇ
All right, but you'll owe me one.
分かりました 一つ貸しにしときますよ
That's the way. I'm in your debt.
そうこなくっちゃ 恩に着るぜ
Hey, you boys.
おい お前ら
Stop making trouble on our turf.
勝手にシマを荒らすんじゃねぇ
We've got nothing to say to you.
あんたとは遣り合いたくねい
Turn around and head back out that—
回れ右して 早速帰れ
Hey there, Uncle Ganzo.
ガンゾの叔父貴
How's the food at Fango's place?
ファンゴの飯は旨いか
Not bad.
Of course, we don't eat free.
勿論 ただ飯って訳にはいかねぇけどな
Could I speak to you for a moment?
ちょっと面貸せ
Come home, Nero.
戻ってこい ネロ
It's just a feud between brothers.
ただの兄弟喧嘩だ
I'll mediate on your behalf.
俺が話しをつけてやる
I taught you and Frate both about women.
お前もフラテも 俺が女を教えてやった
I made you into a real man,
一人前の男にしてやったんだ
so shut up and do as I tell you.
黙って言うことを聞けい
That sure was a rough time.
あれは酷かった
Lots of people in the family miss you.
ファミリーにはお前を慕ってるやつが多い
I doubt it.
どうだかな
It's true. They all wanted to be the one to do this.
本当だ 皆遣りたかってるぜ
Come on.
ったく
I can't argue with you, Uncle.
叔父きには敵わねねぇな
What's going on here?
んだよこれ
What are those accountants doing?
会計士は何をしてた
Profits are half what they were three months ago.
上がりが三か月前の半分だぞ
Nero took the secret brewery.
密造酒はネロが持っていった
To make money bootlegging—
ブーツレッグで稼ぐには...
Well, aren't you naïve?
呑気なもんですね
What was that?
何だと
Even after you met with him, Nero's kept making trouble on our turf.
あなたが会った後も ネロはうちのシマを荒らしてます
At this rate, Fango and Nero are
going to drive us out of business.
このままだとファンゴとネロに潰されますよ
Right now, it's life or death between Nero and me.
もう 兄さんとは生きるか死ぬかなんだ
Are you gonna say that in front of Vincent?
お前 そのセリフをヴィンセントの前で吐けるのか
Let me use this chance to make things clear.
この際だ はっきりさせておきましょう
Nero is the enemy of the family,
ネロはファミリーの敵です
and Don Galassia wants Frate to take over the family.
ドン ガラッシアもフラテが後を継ぐことを希望していますしね
What's Fango doing?
ファンゴの動きがどうだ
He probably already knows where the Lodge is.
ロッチの場所はもう知られてるだろうな
あんなもん
Who cares? Without the recipe, it's just a big steam bath.
酒のレシピがなけりゃ ただのでっかい蒸し風呂だ
Which means it's Corteo we need to worry about.
となると コルテオが心配だ
He'll be fine. Barbero is with him.
大丈夫 バルベロがついてくれてる
It's onion soup.
オニオンスープよ
I remember. Mama Connie
used to make it all the time.
コニー母さんがよく作ってくれたっけな
Can't we go back to the way things were?
もう一度 昔みたいになれないの
I've always supported Dad to protect the family.
俺はファミリーを守るために親父を支えてきた
I plan to keep doing it.
これからもそうするつもりだ
You're wrong.
違うだろう
兄さんが考えてるのは
All you're thinking about is your cheap pride.
薄っぺらいプライドのことだけだ
プライドをなくしたら
There's no point in protecting the
family if we don't have our pride.
ファミリーを守る意味すらなくなっちまうだろうが
If we go against the Galassias, the family will be crushed!
ガラッシアに逆らったら ファミリーは潰されるんだぞ
We'll lose everything!
元も子もないじゃねえか
So you want to let the Vanettis
be swallowed up by the Galassias?
ガラッシアはバネッチィを飲み込んじまうつもりだ
Our only choice is to fight.
戦うしかねんだよ
Why can't you understand that?
なんで分からねんだ
Fio married Ronaldo to keep that from happening.
そうならない為に 姉さんはロナルドと結婚した
But you ruined—
なのに 兄さんがめちくちゃ...
You're Ronaldo's puppet.
お前はロナルドの操る人形なんだよ
You always... always, always...
いつも いつも いつも...
Ever since we were children,
you just did whatever you wanted.
兄さんは子供の頃からやりたいことだけやってきた
You never went to Sunday mass.
日曜の礼拝にも行かないで
You played around however you wanted.
好き勝手に遊んでた
I invited you, but you never came.
お前は誘っても来なかったよな
You were scared of Dad.
いつも親父を怖がってた
You've always looked down on me like that!
兄さんはそうやって いつも俺を見下してきたん
But Ronaldo is different.
だけど ロナルドが違う
He acknowledges me.
俺を認めてくれる
Power's not something you have acknowledged.
力は認めてもらうもんじゃねえ
You prove it for yourself.
自分で示すもんだ
Don't talk down to me!
そんなこと言うな
自分のわがままで
It's your selfishness that ruined our family!
ファミリーをむちゃくちゃしてやがって
If you'd just die, our family would go back to—
お前さえ死ねば ファミリーは元通り
That's enough.
いい加減にして
Brother, please, talk to Ronaldo.
兄さん ロナルドと話し合って
Maybe the Galassias would take this city...
もしかしたら この町はガラッシアに取られるかもしれない
But our family would go back to normal.
でも 家族は元に戻るわ
You're both the same.
あんた達は2人とも同じ
What "family" are you even talking about?!
あんた達の言ってる「ファミリー」っては何
Brothers killing each other...
兄弟で殺し合って
What kind of family is that?!
何がファミリーよ
I don't care about that stuff!
そんなのどうでもいい
I just don't want to see brothers...
to see family killing each other.
兄弟で家族で殺し合うことだけはやめて
No matter what...
絶対に
It's gotten cold.
冷めちまったなあ
I'll work things out with Ronaldo.
ロナルドと話をつける
Did the reunion make you nostalgic?
久々の再会で里心がついたのか?
Throw off the cheap sentimentality.
安い感傷捨てろ
With Frate, it's kill or be killed.
フラテとはやるかやられるかだ
He's still my brother.
あいつは血を分けた兄弟だ
Family's more important than anything.
なりよりも大切な家族なんだ
I had a little brother like him once.
俺にもそん弟がいた
I'll let you meet him soon.
そのうちに合わせてやるよ
Nero's going to die if this keeps up.
このままだと ネロは死ぬ
What are you talking about?
何の話だ
Nero says he's going to work things out with Ronaldo,
ネロはロナルドと話をつけると言ってる
but things have gone too far for that to work now.
だけど もうそんな状況じゃねえ
You saved Nero back at the Vanetti mansion, right?
前にヴァネッティの屋敷でもネロを助けてくれたかなぁ
Yes.
I need your help again.
もう一度力を貸してくれ
I'd do anything for Nero.
ネロのためなら何だってやる
Tomorrow's Sunday, right?
明日は日曜日だったなぁ
Every week like clockwork, huh?
毎週 律儀なことだな
I didn't ask you to come with me.
別に付き合ってくれとは言ったねえ
I heard from Nero.
ネロから連絡が来た
来週の礼拝の後
He's going to meet me at this
mansion next week after mass.
この屋敷で会うことになりそうだ
Then the Vanetti family will be yours.
これでバネッチィファミリーはお前のものだ
H-Hey...
Damn it...
くそ
Damn, I couldn't finish the job.
くそ 討ち漏らした
Were you hurt?
傷は
Tigre's gonna laugh at me, I bet.
ティグレに笑われちまうな
We'll need to go somewhere to stop the bleeding.
どこかで止血しないとなぁ
The bleeding isn't stopping.
血が止まねえ
By the way, we need to tell Nero about—
そう言や ネロにはこのこと...
Leave Nero to me.
ネロのことは任せておけ
It's Volpe.
ボルペだ
Calm down, Nero wouldn't do something like—
冷静になれ ネロはこんなことをする奴...
Give me a break!
ふさげるな
He almost killed us!
俺達は 殺されかけたんだぞ
And Ronaldo, of all people...
よりによって ロナルドが...
Which means now, it's kill or be killed.
こうなったら やるか やられるかだ
I can't live this way anymore.
もう 嫌だ こんな生活
How much longer...
何時まで...
He's just rattling your chain.
ただの挑発だ
Don Vanetti's in this mansion.
この屋敷にはドン ヴァネッティもいる
He can't do anything serious.
大したことは出来ない
Let's leave the city.
町を出よう
If we go to the Galassias in Chicago—
シカゴのガラッシアの所に
Don't act like a child!
甘えてんじゃねぇ
I'll work something out.
おれが何とかしてやる
Have yourself a nice nap.
今 ゆっくり休め
Damn it...
クソ
I want to talk to Nero.
ネロと話し合いたい
That's what you wanted, right?
お前が望んていた事だろう
I'll hear him out.
願いを聞いてやる
Now, after everything?
今更そんなこと?
At this rate, Frate will be killed by Nero,
このままいけば フラテはネロにやられ
and the family will be crushed by the Galassias.
ファミリーはガラッシアに潰されつ
Nero will die as well,
ネロの命も
and so will our child.
そして 俺とお前の子も
But I can save them all.
だが 俺なら救ってやれる
Nero, Frate, the whole family.
ネロもフラテも ファミリーも
You haven't told them about the baby yet, right?
子供のことはまだ話していないんだろう
Tell Nero.
ネロに伝えろ
This baby is our hope...
この子こそ 希望だ
The symbol of reconciliation
between Galassias and Vanettis.
ガラッシアとヴァネッティとの和解の象徴
This child will restore everything to its proper path.
この子が 全てをあるべき道に戻してくれる
You've been working hard, huh?
ご活躍だな
You really are the guy destined to
become the don of the Vanettis.
やっぱりお前はヴァネッティのドンになる男だ
I'll help you however you want.
いくらでも協力するぜ
Keep it up to the very end!
最後の仕上げまできっちりな
How many of ours have been killed?
一体何人殺された
And how many have we killed?
何人殺したんだ
We all used to be part of the same family...
元は同じファミリーだったのに
Nero.
ネロ
Phone call for you, from Fio.
電話だ フィオから
Fio?
フィオ?
Brother, there's something I need to tell you.
兄さん 話があるの
What?
なんだ
Nero's sent a messenger.
Should I let him through?
ネロの使いの者が来た 通していいか
You pat him down?
ボディーチェックは
He's clean.
大丈夫だ
These are for you, Fio, from Nero.
フィオさんにネロから
Where's my brother?
兄さんは
He said he'd be a little late.
少し遅れるそうです
I see...
そう
You think he'll really come?
本当に来るんだろうな
Of course.
勿論
He said he'd just be an hour late.
遅れると言っても 一時間程度です
I'm determined to talk to him this time.
この際 腹を割って話したい
Just me, Nero, and Fio.
俺とネロとフィオの三人だけで
Yes, that's what Nero wants as well.
ええ ネロもそのつもりです
Goodbye.
では
Just to be safe.
用心の為だ
Don't worry.
大丈夫だ
I'm sure it'll work out.
きっと上手くいくさ
Are you going to kill my brother?
兄さんを殺すの?
Vanetti's only option is to
become a puppet to the Galassias.
ヴァネッティはガラッシアの人形になるしかない
Frate understands that.
フラテにはそれが分かってる
But Nero...
しかし ネロは
Don't you worry. It'll all—
心配するな すぐ...
Fio...
フィオ...
I'm sorry...
ごめんなさい
Damn Vanettis...
ヴァ...ヴァネッティめ
It was the only way to protect Frate...
to protect my family.
フラテを 家族を守るには こうするしか
Curse y—
呪われ...
Buona notte.
意大利語:晚安的意思
ボウナ ノッテ
What's wrong, Frate?
どうした フラテ
You're looking ill.
顔色が悪いぞ
How long are you gonna stay cooped up in here?
何時まで そこに閉じこもってる
It's all over.
全部終わったんだ
Go out to the country for some fresh air.
暫く田舎の空気でも吸ってこい
I'm never coming back to this house, am I?
もう 俺がこの家に帰ってくることはないんだろう
I never missed mass.
俺は一度も礼拝を休まなかった
You always did whatever you wanted...
兄さんは何時も勝手なことばかりしてた
And yet, you're the one Dad cared about.
なのに 父さんが可愛がったのは兄さんだった
I always envied you so much.
俺はずっと 兄さんが羨ましかった
Dad acknowledged you...
父さんに認められて
Dad loved you.
父さんはお前を愛してた
I don't want to be loved! I want to be acknowledged!
俺は愛されたいんじゃあい 認められたいんだ
What a load of nonsense.
迷惑な話だ
How many people did you drag into your little brothers' feud?
お前達の兄弟喧嘩に 一体何人付き合わされたんだろうが
Why don't you just put an end to it already?
もういい加減 終わりにしたらどうだ
I'm not afraid.
俺は怖がってなんて...自分で示す
I'll prove it for myself.
Frate, don't do it.
フラテ 止めろ
Do it, Frate.
やれ フラテ
Frate is the one who killed Ronaldo.
ロナルドを殺したのはフラテです
だからネロは ガラッシアへの忠誠を示す為 弟を手にかけた
That's why Nero killed his brother,
to prove his loyalty to the Galassias.
弟を手に掛けた
Nero...
ネロ
Starting today, I'll be your brother.
今日からは俺が兄弟だ